# **RESUME**

## Cherma Pandian T

38A, Arasamaram 1st Street, Avarampalayam, Coimbatore-641006

E-Mail - chermap and ian@gmail.com

**Mob** - +91 95780 80066

# **Summary**

GIS professional (3D&2D) with 12+ years of experience in various Survey/GIS & Photogrammetry projects known for Development of GIS database, GIS Data collection, Land base Creation, GIS Data creation(Vectorization), Data Cleanup, Data migration, Geo-referencing, Spatial & Network Analysis, Topology Validation, Map Creation, Stereo plotting, DTM & DSM Editing, Field Survey (Land, Utility, Property tax), Tender Bidding, Project handling and Personal approach to clients and co-workers as well for monitoring, delivering and implementing advanced solutions to improve the project process. Now seeks the next big career challenge and an opportunity to apply my knowledge and expertise on a larger scale.

# **Areas of Expertise**

- ♣ Geographic Information System
- Training
- ♣ Budget / Resource Planning
- ♣ Team Leadership
- ♣ Client Relation/Vendor Management
- ♣ Operations/Support Management

# **Technical Expertise**

ESRI ArcGIS

- QGIS
- AutoCAD/AutoCAD Map
- Microstation
- ♣ Google Earth/Map
- Open Street Map

DT Master

Summit Evolution

MS Office

DGPS Devices handling

# **Education**

2016-2018 Annamalai University

**Bachelor of Computer Applications** 

2001-2004 Arasan Ganesan Polytechnic College

**Diploma in Electronics & Communication Engineering** 

# **Professional Experience**

# Redleaf Technologies Pvt. Ltd, Coimbatore

Associate Project Manager (Oct 2014 - Till now)

Working as an Associate project manager to managing the GIS and Survey projects and being the part of new project tender bidding process like attending pre-bid meetings, technical document preparation and Costing & resource plan preparation etc.,

- Interact with clients to understand project requirements.
- Analyze and developed the cost-effective GIS solutions to complete the project with in the budget
- Worked with clients and project team to determine the project schedule and deliverables.
- Change of project work plans and resource plan based on the project progress & requirements.
- Plan, coordinate and oversee the project activities to ensure on-time delivery
- Respond to customer enquiries and concerns professionally.
- Technical Guidance & support given to GIS application development team for creating new tools and routines for GIS data services projects.
- Provide necessary technical support and training to new employees

## Navayuga Infotech Pvt. Ltd., Chennai

Team Leader Survey/GIS (Aug 2011 - Sep 2014)

Worked as a Team Lead to managing the GIS and Survey activities of R-APRDP project of in various towns for preparation of TNEB Overhead & Unger ground Electrical Network Assets and Consumer index mapping.

- Planning and Execution of Survey and GIS activities closure as per project requirements.
- Coordinate with field survey team GIS related queries and requirements
- Technical support to the GIS/Survey teams and vendors
- Monitoring the Survey & GIS team performance
- Tracking the production reports and share with management in weekly and monthly basis.
- Responsible for the Quality assurance and final data delivery to the Client
- Plan & Initiate the set of tools for auto attribution & DTR structure arrangement to reduce the productive hours
- Creating some basic scripts in excel for auto attribution in VB & Python
- Supporting the process of development and implementation of all other application modules

# DSM Soft Pvt. Ltd., Trichy

Senior Engineer 3D Mapping (Jan 2007 - Jul 2011)

Worked as a Senior Engineer in various types of GIS 2D & 3D projects

- Data conversion or creation (Digitization) of land base, Electrical Network,
- Water network, Pipeline network, Telecom Network Etc.,
- Land Parcel Mapping
- Geo referencing of various type of raster and Vector data
- Data cleanup and Topology validation
- Data Migration in various formats
- Auto cad drafting like, Isometric piping, 2D piping etc.
- DSM and DTM editing (Photogrammetry)
- Stereo plotting (Photogrammetry)
- 3D Building Modelling (Photogrammetry)
- Quality check and Quality assurance team player
- Team player in pilot projects

# Dayspring Electronics Pvt. Ltd. Sivakasi (Tata Teleservices) Installation & Repair Technician (May 2004 -Dec 2006)

- Installation of new connections of UTP & PTB
- Attend and rectify the customer complaints
- Stock maintenance.

# **Professional Accomplishments**

- Successfully completed the R-APDRP utility Survey/GIS Project in Chennai Central Zone with the new role as a Team Leader before the deadline of the project.
- Got the Best Performer award in the year of 2014 for the innovative ideas and efforts for the completion R-APDRP Project of Chennai Central Zone In Navayuga Infotech Pvt Ltd.
- Successfully completed the R-APDRP Updation Project of Chennai South & North Zone, Cuddalore, Pudukkottai, Aranthangi, Trichy towns as a Project lead with in the timeline as well as the budget.
- Worked closely with Clients (TNEB, KSEB & Karur Railways) and received client approvals as well as the appreciation.

# **Major Project Expertise**

## R-APDRP, KSEB ((Kerala State Electricity Board)

43 Towns in Kerala State

**Scope:** The focus of the program is on the actual demonstrable performance in terms of AT&C loss reduction, establishment of the reliable and automated sustainable systems for collection of base line data, adoption of information technology in the areas of energy accounting, consumer care and strengthening of Distribution network of State Power Utilities

As the part of R-APDRP project, the electrical network changes of 43 towns to be surveyed and mapped in to the GIS Application

#### **Process:**

- DGPS Survey of Electrical network changes by periodical Survey
- Updation of spatial and technical attributes of these surveyed data mapped into the online GIS application
- Submission & Getting approval in section wise from KSEB officials after verification

#### Position Held:

Associate Project Manager

# GTDC, (Goa Tourism Development Corporation Ltd)

**GOA State** 

**Scope:** Preparation of Base Map and Development of Web-Based Tourist Information System Using GIS for Entire GOA under Swadesh Darshan Costal Circuit I and II of Ministry Of Tourism

#### **Process:**

- Prepared the Grid scenes for future usage like Map Book creations, Smart Asset ID creation etc. based on the standards defined in NUIS and international standards
- Worked with GTDC and finalize the database structure and design based on the international design standards
- Preparation of large-scale base map by digitize all the physical features such as Buildings, Beaches and Various tourist activities, Roads, Water bodies, Shacks and other visible features from satellite imagery (0.3m Resolution).
- The survey data of each and every tourist spot and the ground truthing of prepared GIS base map features
- Symbol creation, Layering, Edge matching, Topological integrity, and data base linking
- Preparation of ward & Beach wise maps depicting all entities in the pdf at the size of 1:1000 scal3
- Published as a web service (Map & Feature service) for further application development and usages

#### **Position Held:**

Associate Project Manager

## R-APDRP, TNEB (Tamil Nadu Electricity Board)

110 Towns in Tamil Nadu State

**Scope:** The focus of the program is on the actual demonstrable performance in terms of AT&C loss reduction, establishment of the reliable and automated sustainable systems for collection of base line data, adoption of information technology in the areas of energy accounting, consumer care and strengthening of Distribution network of State Power Utilities

#### **Process:**

- Base map/Land base Creation from the satellite image (0.5m Resolution)
- Ground truthing of base map features
- GIS mapping of the entire distribution network from substation to consumer end by periodical field survey
- Consumer indexing by periodical on field survey
- Map album Generation for the entire distribution network
- Submission & Getting approval in section wise from TNEB officials after verification

#### **Position Held:**

Survey/GIS Team Lead

# Other 2D &3D Project Expertise

## **Southern Railways**

Karur

**Scope:** DGPS Survey of Railway buildings and Boundary demarcations and with its all electrical and water networks and all utilities integrated into GIS applications for Southern railways

# **INCOIS (Indian National Centre for Ocean Information Services)**

Puducherry & Cuddalore

**Scope:** As a part of Tsunami warning and disaster management system, Survey of Socio Economic details of all the buildings in Tsunami vulnerable areas and mapping into GIS application.

## **FONE**

**USA Client** 

**Scope:** Geo referencing of cartographic maps and Creation of Digital Parcel lines containing a graphic representation of Parcel boundary information with special care of data correctness is to be taken, like, no overshoots/undershoots, proper layering, & Topological integrity

## JDS

**Germany Client** 

**Scope:** Various AutoCAD drafting projects like Isometric piping, 2D Piping, Fabrication Detail, Pressure vessels, and Structural detailing

# Darwin Mapping (3D stereo plotting & DTM editing)

Australia Client

**Scope:** Feature conversion of all plannimetric features and to supply 1:25000 topographic mapping which includes break line, which help the generation of 1m contours as well as the ortho of Nitmilutes national park in Australia.

## Flemish Mapping (3D stereo plotting)

Denmark Client

**Scope:** The project is based on feature conversion of all plannimetric features with the tolerance level of 0.1m with the huge technical specifications.

## ADS 40 (3D DTM& DSM Editing)

**UK Client** 

**Scope:** The scope of the project is to edit customer supplied 5m DTM & DSM for an area of 38000sqkm with the tolerance level of 0.5m

# **Personal Details**

Father's Name - Thangam.M

Date of Birth - 08th October 1984

Sex - Male
Nationality - Indian

Passport No - J5663860

Date of Issue - 1st March 2011

Date of Expiry - 28th February 2021

Current Location - Coimbatore, Tamilnadu.

Marital Status - Married

Permanent Address - 5/535, Samypuram Colony

Pallaptti, Sivakasi -626189

Languages Known - Tamil, English

## **Declaration**

I am confident of my ability to work in a team. I solemnly declared that the information provided by me in this application is correct and complete to the best of my knowledge

Cherma Pandian.T